▍2026 多伦多 WTA1000 第三轮
伊埃拉 6-3 5-7 6-4 麦克纳莉 · 赛后新闻发布会
Okay, we'll go ahead and get started.
好 我们开始吧
Alex, what a win tonight
亚历克斯 今晚这场赢得漂亮
and an amazing atmosphere out there.
现场气氛也太棒了
Um, it was a really hard-fought battle
这是一场苦战
against a great opponent.
对手也很强
Just give us your keys to the match today.
说说今天这场的关键吧
Yeah, uh, thanks for waiting, guys.
谢谢大家等着
Um, I think it was it
我是说
was a really tough match today.
今天这场真的很难打
Um, for many reasons.
原因有好几个
one being also that Caty
其中一个是麦克纳莉
is such a big fighter and I think she's got
她太能拼了 而且
definitely some some good weapons
她确实有些厉害的武器
and and yeah, it was a tight was a tight one.
这场打得很胶着
Alex, congratulations on an incredible win.
亚历克斯 恭喜这场精彩的胜利
After the match, you kind of just sat there
赛后你坐在那儿
and just
就那样
Yeah. Can you explain that moment
能说说那一刻吗
and just what was going through your mind
你当时在想什么
and
还有
Yeah.
嗯
Yeah. Um I think this match
我觉得这场
was was really challenging for me.
对我来说真的很有挑战
I think the whole two weeks I guess
这整整两周
have been very challenging
都很有挑战
and each match that I've played
我打的每一场
has presented its unique set of challenges.
都有各自不同的难题
Um yeah, today obviously was really close
今天这场确实很胶着
and I think you know like I'm I'm
我
really of course I'm feeling the effects
确实感觉到了
of you know just everything
这一切带来的影响
and I think I'm really doing
我真的在尽力
my best like I said on court
就像我在场上说的那样
to um you know to stay professional
保持专业
and stick to what I know but everything
做我熟悉的事 但这一切
of course like this past two weeks I've
这两周我
been feeling emotions so extremely
情绪一直很强烈
because of the the circumstances
因为这些经历
which is which is a great thing.
这其实是件好事
You know, I love I'm I think I'm quite a
我觉得我是个
sentimental person.
挺重感情的人
Um but at the same time,
但同时
it's just kind of like finding that balance.
也在找一个平衡
So, I think um I'm really proud
所以我挺为自己骄傲
of how I handled today
今天处理得不错
and and and what I did on court.
场上的表现也是
Yeah, Alex, there there were so many times
亚历克斯 这场好多次
during the match where you were tested,
你都被逼到了极限
you know, you had to come up
你不得不
from early holes in the games.
从落后的局面里爬出来
What are you kind
你
of telling yourself in the moment uh
那种时候心里在想什么
when you're fighting back
当你从落后的比分里
from those early deficits and games?
往回拼的时候
Yeah, I think I need I try
我会
to focus more on factual things.
更专注在事实上
So, um I mean of course there
当然
are many external factors
有很多外部因素
but there are things that also I can control
但也有我能控制的部分
and I'm I was aware of the situation.
我很清楚当时的局面
I know that she was playing well.
我知道她打得很好
Um I know that I
我也知道我
was missing certain balls here and there.
有些球没处理好
So I tried to just play the point better
所以我就想把这一分打
than the point before.
得比上一分更好
Yeah.
嗯
Hi Alex, well done.
你好 亚历克斯 打得漂亮
So, the the Blue Dinosaur super fan
那个蓝色恐龙的超级粉丝
was back today.
今天又来了
Oh my gosh.
天呐
Oh my god. How just talk
天呐 说说
about your new super fan
你这位新粉丝吧
and how much are you noticing him,
你注意到他了吗
you know, throughout the
整场比赛
You know, today I didn't see him
其实今天我没看见他
in the crowd.
在人群里
I knew he I know he was there.
但我知道他在
People told me he was there.
有人跟我说他来了
Um but wow, what a legend.
他真的很传奇
Like it was so funny
第一晚我第一次看见他的时候
when I first saw him the first night.
真的太好笑了
Amazing. And I think it
真是 我是说
was just I don't know.
说不上来
It just it was like such a light funny spin
就是给大家支持我的方式
to kind of like how how people support me.
添了一种轻松好玩的调调
It just comes out in very unique ways
每个人支持的方式都很不一样
and I think he's really stood out.
他这个真的很突出
Hi Alex. Well done tonight.
你好 亚历克斯 今晚打得好
I noticed in the third set
我注意到决胜盘
after you won a point you asked the crowd
你赢下一分之后让观众
to to cheer louder.
喊得更大声
You you were them on to cheer.
你在带动他们喊
Players have talked about how a crowd
有球员说过观众
can you know will a player to victory.
能把球员一路喊向胜利
Did you feel that tonight,
今晚你有这种感觉吗
especially in the third set, that the crowd
尤其是决胜盘 观众
was really even more supportive than you
是不是比平时
than than normal?
更给力
Yes, I think um I mean
没错
in that point specifically,
就那一分来说
um I think I wanted to kind
我当时是想
of like I I was hyped so I wanted to kind
我很兴奋 就想
of like um share that with the crowd
把这份情绪分享给观众
and obviously also try to take
也想
in their energy.
借一下他们的能量
Um but I think it was I I think it
我觉得那
was a pretty good point.
是很精彩的一分
uh don't remember quite so well.
具体细节记不太清了
Um yeah,
嗯
normally I try to just be indifferent
平时我尽量表现得平静
and kind of like, you know, but I think
但我是说
that point was specifically um I'm sorry,
那一分特别一点 抱歉
I can't find the word.
我一时想不出词
It was Yeah, I wanted that point.
就是 我太想拿下那一分了
Yeah.
嗯
Alex, oh, you had such a nice warm hug
亚历克斯 你在网前
with um Caty at the net.
和麦克纳莉抱得很暖
Can you share what exchange you
能说说你们
had uh what words you exchanged
在网前说了些什么吗
at the net?
交换了什么话
Yeah. No, I obviously I think there
我是说
was a huge mutual respect
我们之间有很深的相互尊重
for the great match that we had.
为了这场精彩的比赛
Um she told me congratulations
她跟我说恭喜
and she said um thanks
还说 谢谢
for letting me be a part
让我加入
of this which is which is incredibly kind
这一切 这句话真的很暖
and gracious from her.
也很大度
Um, yeah, I think it's, yeah, super gracious
我觉得她真的很有风度
and and a lot of respect for Caty.
我也很敬重麦克纳莉
I also wanted to ask how tired you are.
我还想问你有多累
I noticed right after the match,
我注意到赛后
you put your legs up like that.
你把腿那样抬起来
So, how hard did you have to push tonight,
今晚你拼到什么程度
Alex, to get that win?
才拿下这场
Yeah, I needed to push a lot.
我拼得很狠
I am as tired as one can be at this stage.
这个阶段能有多累我就有多累
You can imagine a lot of matches, but um,
打了这么多场 但
you know, that's the job.
这就是这份工作
I'm I'm ready.
我准备好了
I I'm excited for another match.
我很期待下一场
I'm gonna do my best to recover
我会尽力恢复
and and you know start again from zero.
然后重新从零开始
Alex, obviously a big part
亚历克斯 你打法
of your game is kind of being aggressive
很大一部分是主动进攻
and taking the ball early,
抢在早点击球
but I'm just curious like the slice you've
但我很好奇 你一直在练
been kind of working
那个切削球
that into your especially in the last,
尤其是最近
you know, few tournaments.
这几站
Like how much of a weapon
你觉得切削球
do you believe like having the slice as part
作为你武器库的一部分
of your arsenal can help you going forward?
往后能帮你多少
I think it's important to to know how
我觉得重要的是知道怎么
to change rhythm, I guess.
去改变节奏
Um, yeah,
嗯
I think it's I guess it's been pretty effective
我觉得它挺管用
because I've been doing pretty well.
因为我这段打得还不错
But, um, it's it's, you know,
但它
one among the other other things
只是我众多武器里
that I have.
的其中一个
Yeah.
嗯
Alex, I'm just wondering how
亚历克斯 我想问问
are you doing physically?
你身体感觉怎么样
I know you think you
我知道你好像
had like an ankle moment.
脚踝出过状况
How are you how are you doing physically?
你现在身体怎么样
And do you expect
你会担心
that to maybe be a concern for you
这会不会变成隐患
as the tournament progresses?
随着赛事往下打
Yeah. Um I kind of rolled my ankle
我在第二盘
in in the that second set.
有点崴到脚踝
There was like I hit the forehand
我打了一个正手
and I landed kind of wrong.
落地的姿势不太对
Um I called the phys uh the physio
我叫了理疗师
and I think I was a little I was like,
我当时心里想
"Oh, I don't know what happened,
我不知道发生了什么
you know." Um cuz it happened so fast.
因为一切发生得太快了
But luckily there's there's nothing wrong
但还好没什么大问题
with it.
没事
Um and it
而且
was no no serious no serious problems
不是什么严重的问题
but I mean uh yeah today
不过今天
was physically it pushed me a lot and I
身体上真的很拼
have a lot of matches in my in you know
我这段打了很多场
in the bag but that's goes for good
这既是好事
and bad and you know I think this is also
也有代价 我觉得这也是
a learning process there um you know
一个学习的过程
we're athletes so that's kind
我们是运动员
of physical is it's like a huge part
身体状况本来就是
of our job so um I think I
这份工作很大的一部分
have a great team who's going
我有个很棒的团队
to help me recover
会帮我恢复
and and I have I have high hopes
我对接下来这站
for for the rest of the tournament.
也很有信心
Playing Bencic next, what are your thoughts
接下来对阵本西奇
on Bencic?
有什么想法吗
Yeah.
嗯
Oh, super excited.
我特别期待
I It's going to be the first time
这是我第一次
that I'm facing her.
和她交手
And of course, Belinda is is I mean,
贝琳达
she is has accomplished so much in tennis.
网球生涯成就太多了
And um of course I remember watching
我还记得看她
her um win the Olympic medal.
拿下奥运奖牌的那一刻
So I think it's I'm really excited
我真的很期待
to be on court again.
能再站上球场
Yeah.
嗯
Thank you. Thanks guys.
谢谢大家
Good night.
晚安